Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another edition here with us at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一期节目。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we are doing the third part of our Old English series and today we're transported
今天我们继续“老式英语”系列的第三部分，今天我们将被带回到
back to the 1970s.
20世纪70年代。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to learn some 1970s slang, some phrases that were really popular back
所以我们将学习一些70年代的俚语，一些在当时非常流行
in the 70s but are also still in use today.
但至今仍在使用的短语。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's going to be a very cool lesson today.
所以今天的课会非常酷。
And before we start with the dialogue, let's take a look at some of the words that we're
在我们开始对话之前，先来看看一些
going to find in Vocabulary Preview.
在词汇预览中会出现的单词。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Well we have two words for you in Vocabulary Preview and they're both found in the dialogue.
词汇预览中我们有两个单词，它们都会出现在对话里。
The first one, roller rink.
第一个是：roller rink。
A roller rink.
一个roller rink。
Okay, so a roller rink.
好，所以roller rink。
Let's break that down and let's look at the first part.
我们来分解一下，先看第一部分。
All right.
好的。
So roller.
所以roller。
You might recognize this from roller blades or roller skates.
你可能从roller blades（直排轮滑鞋）或roller skates（四轮溜冰鞋）中认出这个词。
Okay, so yeah, when you go roller blading, roller skating, those things that you put
对，就是你去玩直排轮滑或四轮溜冰时，那些穿在脚上
on your feet to skate.
用来滑行的东西。
Right, wheels, not like a blade or a knife.
对，是轮子，不是刀片或刀子。
Exactly.
正是。
So that's roller.
所以那就是roller。
And what about rink?
那rink呢？
Rink is the place where you do skating.
Rink是你进行溜冰的地方。
Okay, so if you go to a roller rink, it's this big area where everyone can roller blade
好，所以如果你去roller rink，那是一个大场地，每个人都可以在那里玩直排轮滑
or roller skate.
或四轮溜冰。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And what about the next word?
那下一个词呢？
A block.
A block。
Block.
Block。
Okay, so this is a noun, a block.
好，这是一个名词，a block。
And a block is a part of a city that is surrounded by four streets.
Block是城市中被四条街道包围的一部分。
Okay, so a city is made up of many blocks.
好，所以城市由许多blocks组成。
Yeah.
对。
And everyone lives on a block.
每个人都住在一个block上。
Exactly.
正是。
So it's a square within the city.
所以它是城市里的一个方块区域。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
So these are the two words that we previewed and we're going to listen to them now in the
这就是我们预览的两个单词，现在我们将在
dialogue.
对话中听到它们。
We're going to hear two guys just talking about normal everyday things, but we're going
我们会听到两个家伙在谈论日常琐事，但我们将
to be listening to them in 1970.
在1970年的背景下听。
Hey man, how's it hanging?
嘿，老兄，最近怎么样？
Hey man, everything is just groovy, baby.
嘿，老兄，一切都棒极了，宝贝。
Did you go to the roller rink on Saturday?
你周六去溜冰场了吗？
I heard it was far out, man.
我听说那里超酷，老兄。
I wanted to, but I ran into this foxy lady that just moved to my block.
我想去，但我遇到了一个刚搬到我街区来的性感美女。
I was chatting her up a bit and then we mellowed out at her place.
我跟她聊了一会儿，然后在她家放松了一下。
Right on, right on.
没错，没错。
Well, Jim went to the rink with Sherry and he said it was dynamite.
嗯，Jim和Sherry去了溜冰场，他说那里棒极了。
He was low on bread, but Sherry paid for everything.
他钱不够，但Sherry付了所有费用。
Gravy!
太棒了！
Jim is such a jive turkey, man.
Jim真是个虚伪的家伙，老兄。
He's always hitting me up for cash.
他老是找我借钱。
Anyway, you want a book and go grab some grub?
总之，你想快点走然后去弄点吃的吗？
Yeah, man.
好啊，老兄。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
OK, groovy dialogue.
好，很棒的对话。
Yeah, really nice, huh?
是啊，真不错，对吧？
Alright, so some interesting language in here.
好的，这里有一些有趣的语言。
Like we said, it sounds a bit strange, but a lot of this is still used today in modern
就像我们说的，听起来有点奇怪，但其中很多在今天的现代
English.
英语中仍在使用。
So why don't we look at some of these words in Language Takeaway.
那我们不如在“语言要点”中看看这些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, on Language Takeaway today, we have the first word, far out.
好的，今天的语言要点中，第一个词是far out。
Far out.
Far out。
That was far out.
那太far out了。
To be far out.
很far out。
OK, so it's just another way of saying cool.
好，这只是cool的另一种说法。
Cool, that was nice.
酷，那很好。
Yeah.
对。
It was really cool.
真的很酷。
So they went to the roller rink, it was far out, it was really cool, but the other guy
所以他们去了溜冰场，那里很far out，很酷，但另一个人
couldn't go because he saw a foxy lady.
去不了，因为他看到了一个foxy lady。
A foxy lady.
A foxy lady。
OK, foxy lady.
好，foxy lady。
So basically a foxy lady is a really good looking or sexy woman.
基本上foxy lady是指一个非常好看或性感的女人。
Right, commonly you would hear some men refer to an attractive woman as a fox.
对，你常会听到一些男人把有魅力的女人称为fox。
OK, so foxy lady.
好，所以foxy lady。
Now, Marco, can we say a foxy man?
现在，Marco，我们能说a foxy man吗？
No, this is a phrase that you would only use for women.
不，这个短语只用于女性。
OK, so foxy lady.
好，所以foxy lady。
Foxy lady.
Foxy lady。
So after he met up with the foxy lady, they both just decided to mellow out at her place.
所以在他遇到那个foxy lady之后，他们俩决定在她家mellow out。
To mellow out.
To mellow out。
OK, so mellow out.
好，mellow out。
What does this mean exactly?
这到底是什么意思？
Basically just to relax.
基本上就是放松。
Right, so to relax, to take it easy, to mellow out.
对，就是放松、放轻松、mellow out。
So what did you do on the weekend?
所以你周末做了什么？
Oh, nothing.
哦，没什么。
I just stayed at home and mellowed out.
我就待在家里放松了一下。
OK.
好的。
Alright, and so the response to that was...
好的，然后对此的回应是……
Right on.
Right on。
Right, right on, right on.
对，right on，right on。
And so basically they're saying, OK, good, I agree.
基本上他们在说，好的，不错，我同意。
Yeah, this phrase, you can say as good, yeah, that's nice, or you can also say it as well,
对，这个短语你可以用来表示好、不错，或者也可以表示
correct, correct, I agree.
正确、正确，我同意。
So why don't we listen to some examples of how we can use this word in other situations.
那我们不如听一些例子，看看这个词在其他情境中怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
Right on.
没错。
You got a high score.
你得了高分。
That's amazing.
太棒了。
Example two.
例子二。
You got the job?
你得到那份工作了？
Right on.
太好了。
Example three.
例子三。
Jenny was right when she told me she thought Rick was no good for me.
Jenny说得对，她告诉我Rick不适合我。
I should have listened to her.
我本该听她的。
OK, so I think that's pretty clear.
好，我想这很清楚。
We can see how it means correct or also OK, good.
我们可以看到它表示正确，或者也表示好的、不错。
Alright, right on.
好的，right on。
And now we also have another word that's similar to far out.
现在我们还有另一个和far out类似的词。
He said gravy.
他说了gravy。
Gravy.
Gravy。
Now, if you look it up in a dictionary, it's going to tell you something else, right?
如果你查字典，它会告诉你别的意思，对吧？
Gravy is a sauce you put on meat.
Gravy是浇在肉上的酱汁。
Right.
对。
But in this case, we say gravy is cool.
但在这里，我们说gravy是酷的意思。
It's nice.
很好。
Yep.
对。
Right?
对吧？
So gravy.
所以gravy。
And now, finally, at the end of their conversation, they said, wanna book?
最后，在他们对话结束时，他们说，wanna book？
OK, let's book.
好，let's book。
Book.
Book。
So, to book is a verb.
所以，to book是一个动词。
Yeah, interesting verb.
对，有趣的动词。
It basically means to leave a place quickly.
它基本上意思是快速离开一个地方。
OK, so we have to book.
好，所以我们得book。
The police are coming.
警察来了。
Right.
对。
Or, I got to book, guys.
或者，我得book了，伙计们。
I'm late.
我迟到了。
So, book.
所以，book。
To leave quickly, to leave suddenly.
快速离开，突然离开。
Yep.
对。
And that word is used quite commonly today, isn't it?
那个词今天也很常用，对吧？
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
It's used among like younger people.
它在年轻人中常用。
You would say, yeah, let's book.
你会说，对，let's book。
This party is dead.
这个派对太无聊了。
OK, great.
好，很好。
So, there's a lot of pretty cool phrases in this dialogue.
所以，这个对话里有很多很酷的短语。
Pretty groovy phrases.
很棒的短语。
Why don't we hear them again in context?
我们不如在上下文中再听一遍？
Hey, man.
嘿，老兄。
How's it hanging?
最近怎么样？
Hey.
嘿。
Everything is just groovy, baby.
一切都棒极了，宝贝。
Did you go to the roller rink on Saturday?
你周六去溜冰场了吗？
I heard it was far out, man.
我听说那里超酷，老兄。
I wanted to, but I ran into this foxy lady that just moved to my block.
我想去，但我遇到了一个刚搬到我街区来的性感美女。
I was chatting her up a bit, and then we mellowed out at her place.
我跟她聊了一会儿，然后在她家放松了一下。
Right on, right on.
没错，没错。
Well, Jim went to the rink with Sherry, and he said it was dynamite.
嗯，Jim和Sherry去了溜冰场，他说那里棒极了。
He was low on bread, but Sherry paid for everything.
他钱不够，但Sherry付了所有费用。
Gravy.
太棒了。
Jim is such a jive turkey, man.
Jim真是个虚伪的家伙，老兄。
He's always hitting me up for cash.
他老是找我借钱。
Anyway, you want to book and go grab some grub?
总之，你想快点走然后去弄点吃的吗？
Yeah, man.
好啊，老兄。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
All right.
好的。
So, now that we understand these six words that we saw in Language Takeaway, it's time
所以，现在我们理解了语言要点中的这六个词，是时候
for us now to take a look at some great phrases that we can use today in Fluency Builder.
来看看一些在流利度构建中今天可以用的好短语了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
OK.
好的。
So, at the start of the conversation, there was an interesting way he started talking
在对话开始时，他有一种有趣的方式开始
to his friend, right?
和朋友说话，对吧？
All right.
好的。
He said, how's it hanging?
他说，how's it hanging？
How's it hanging?
How's it hanging？
OK.
好的。
So, basically, how is it going?
所以，基本上就是how is it going？
How's it going?
怎么样？
How are you?
你好吗？
Now, you notice in the spelling that we do have a G at the end, I-N-G, right?
现在，你注意到拼写中结尾有G，I-N-G，对吧？
Yeah, but usually you don't really pronounce the G in this context because it's very informal.
对，但通常在这种非正式语境中，你不会真的发G的音。
So, how's it hanging?
所以，how's it hanging？
How's it hanging?
How's it hanging？
He said everything was just groovy and then he started telling him about how he met a
他说一切都棒极了，然后他开始告诉他关于他如何遇到一个
girl and he chatted her up a bit.
女孩，并和她聊了一会儿。
To chat her up.
To chat her up。
OK.
好的。
So, to chat somebody up.
所以，to chat somebody up。
So, when you chat someone up, you talk with them, right?
所以，当你跟某人搭讪时，就是跟他们聊天，对吧？
Yeah, you're making conversation.
是的，你在进行对话。
But it's more than just conversation, isn't it?
但这不仅仅是对话，对吧？
Yeah, you're trying to be a little bit flirty and maybe say nice romantic phrases or something
对，你试图表现得有点调情，可能说些浪漫的话之类的。
like that.
像那样。
Yeah, so usually it's between a woman and a man, right?
是的，所以通常是在女人和男人之间，对吧？
And it's the man who chats up the woman.
而且是男人去搭讪女人。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
So, a little bit of a sexist phrase here.
所以，这里有点性别歧视的意味。
To chat someone up or to chat up a girl, right?
搭讪某人或搭讪一个女孩，对吧？
OK, so he was chatting her up.
好的，所以他当时在搭讪她。
That's right.
没错。
And so they were talking about how Jim went to the roller rink but he didn't have any
所以他们当时在谈论吉姆去了溜冰场，但他没有带任何
money, right?
钱，对吧？
Because Jim is always hitting his friends up for cash.
因为吉姆总是找朋友借钱。
OK, so to hit someone up.
好的，所以“hit someone up”。
To hit someone up.
“Hit someone up”。
So, before we explain this word, let's listen to some other examples so then we can maybe
所以，在我们解释这个词之前，让我们听一些其他的例子，这样我们也许能
understand the meaning.
理解它的意思。
Example 1.
例子1。
Can you believe Patrick?
你能相信帕特里克吗？
He came up to me a month ago and tried to hit me up for some money.
他一个月前来找我，想跟我借点钱。
Example 2.
例子2。
When I was a kid, I used to always hit my dad up for lunch money.
我小时候，总是找我爸要午餐钱。
Example 3.
例子3。
This is the last time I lend you money.
这是我最后一次借你钱。
Don't even try to hit me up for more.
别想再找我多要了。
All right, so when you hit someone up for something, you ask for it.
好了，所以当你“hit someone up for something”时，就是向某人要东西。
So usually it's to ask for money, right?
所以通常是要钱，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
OK, so to hit someone up.
好的，所以“hit someone up”。
And now for our last phrase.
现在来看我们最后一个短语。
Let's book and let's go grab some grub.
我们走吧，去弄点吃的。
To grab some grub.
“To grab some grub”。
Grab some grub.
“Grab some grub”。
OK, let's break this one down.
好的，我们来分解一下这个短语。
With the final word, grub, what are we talking about?
最后一个词“grub”，我们在说什么？
Grub is an informal way of saying food.
“Grub”是“食物”的非正式说法。
OK, so to grab some grub is to get some food quickly.
好的，所以“to grab some grub”就是快速弄点吃的。
Yeah, let's go get some food.
是的，我们去弄点吃的吧。
All right, so maybe it's time for us to grab some grub.
好了，也许我们该去弄点吃的了。
And while we're doing that, you can listen to the dialogue one last time.
在我们这么做的时候，你可以再听一遍对话。
Hey man, how's it hanging?
嘿，老兄，最近怎么样？
Hey man, everything is just groovy, baby.
嘿，老兄，一切都棒极了，宝贝。
Did you go to the roller rink on Saturday?
你周六去溜冰场了吗？
I heard it was far out, man.
我听说那里很酷，老兄。
I wanted to, but I ran into this foxy lady that just moved to my block.
我想去，但我遇到了一个刚搬到我街区来的迷人女士。
I was chatting her up a bit and then we mellowed out at her place.
我跟她搭讪了一会儿，然后我们在她家放松了一下。
Right on, right on.
没错，没错。
Well, Jim went to the rink with Sherry and he said it was dynamite.
嗯，吉姆和雪莉去了溜冰场，他说那里棒极了。
He was low on bread, but Sherry paid for everything.
他钱不够，但雪莉付了所有费用。
Gravy!
太棒了！
Jim is such a jive turkey, man.
吉姆真是个蠢货，老兄。
He's always hitting me up for cash.
他总是找我借钱。
Anyway, you want a book and go grab some grub?
不管怎样，你想走吗，去弄点吃的？
Yeah, man, I'm starving.
好啊，老兄，我饿死了。
All right, so some interesting phrases and even though some of these words you may not
好了，所以有一些有趣的短语，尽管其中一些词你可能不再
really commonly hear anymore, they might still be used in movies or something that's related
经常听到了，但它们可能仍然用在电影或与迪斯科时代相关的东西里，
to the disco era because it's very, very popular still, right?
因为那个时代现在仍然很流行，对吧？
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And some of our more advanced users could even use a lot of these phrases in a kind
我们的一些高级用户甚至可以用很多这些短语以
of funny way to reference back to 1970.
一种有趣的方式来回溯到1970年。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
So it's fun and well, you will use them or you will hear them from time to time, even
所以这很有趣，而且，你会用到它们，或者你会时不时听到它们，甚至
today.
在今天。
And remember, if you have any questions about the language you hear in these lessons, check
记住，如果你对这些课程中听到的语言有任何疑问，请查看
out our website at EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Exactly.
没错。
We're there to answer any questions and we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里回答任何问题，我们会在那里见到你们。
Thanks for listening and until next time, goodbye.
感谢收听，下次再见，再见。
Bye.
再见。
X